Un minuscule agent pathogène nous a tous rappelé
à quel point la santé humaine est vulnérable et profondément liée
au bien-être des écosystèmes et des autres espèces.
L'Organisation Mondiale de la Santé estime que
60 % de toutes les maladies infectieuses proviennent de différents animaux.
Savoir où se trouvent les espèces qui transmettent des pathogènes responsables de maladies
est important pour la reconnaissance, la gestion et la prévention des menaces potentielles pour la santé.
Grâce aux données partagées par le biais du Système mondial d’information sur la biodiversité,
ou GBIF,
les scientifiques et chercheurs de diverses disciplines
cartographient les espèces impliquées dans les cycles de transmission de maladie
et comment leurs distributions changent.
Such data offers an essential element in
understanding zoonotic and vector-borne diseases
and identifying areas at risk of potential outbreaks.
Policymakers and public health officials can use the resulting insights
to prepare responses, focus surveillance and allocate resources
to protect people’s lives and livelihoods.
When combined with climatic and environmental information,
GBIF-mediated data sometimes reveals
and even predicts sites of disease spillover.
In 2018, an analysis using data from the GBIF network
identified a high-risk hotspot for the Nipah virus outbreak in southern India
just before the disease emerged there.
By contributing to a "One Health" approach
that recognizes the intimate connection
between the well-being of humans, animals, and ecosystems,
data shared through GBIF helps us
understand and prepare for potential disease risks,
reducing the many costs of future disease outbreaks
to keep people and the planet healthy.
To learn more about the connections
GBIF reveals between biodiversity and human health
visit www.gbif.org/health