小さな病原体に私たちは気付かされました。
人間の健康がいかに脆弱で、生態系や生物種の健全さと
いかに深く結びついているかということです。
世界保健機構（WHO）は全ての感染症のうち
60%が動物由来であると推定しました。
Knowing where the species that transmit disease-causing pathogens occur
is important for recognizing, managing, and preventing potential health threats.
With data shared through the Global Biodiversity Information Facility,
or GBIF,
scientists and researchers from various disciplines
map the species involved in cycles of disease transmission
and how their distributions are changing.
Such data offers an essential element in
understanding zoonotic and vector-borne diseases
and identifying areas at risk of potential outbreaks.
Policymakers and public health officials can use the resulting insights
to prepare responses, focus surveillance and allocate resources
to protect people’s lives and livelihoods.
When combined with climatic and environmental information,
GBIF-mediated data sometimes reveals
and even predicts sites of disease spillover.
In 2018, an analysis using data from the GBIF network
identified a high-risk hotspot for the Nipah virus outbreak in southern India
just before the disease emerged there.
By contributing to a "One Health" approach
that recognizes the intimate connection
between the well-being of humans, animals, and ecosystems,
data shared through GBIF helps us
understand and prepare for potential disease risks,
reducing the many costs of future disease outbreaks
to keep people and the planet healthy.
To learn more about the connections
GBIF reveals between biodiversity and human health
visit www.gbif.org/health