一种微小的病原体提醒我们所有人，
人类健康与生态系统和其它物种的福祉是多么脆弱，
又是多么紧密地联系在一起。
世界卫生组织估计，
60%的传染病起源于不同的动物。
了解传播致病病原体的物种发生在何处，
对于识别、管理和预防潜在的健康威胁至关重要。
通过全球生物多样性信息设施
(GBIF)共享的数据，
来自不同学科的科学家和研究人员
绘制了疾病传播周期中涉及的物种
以及它们的分布如何变化的地图。
这些数据是
了解人畜共患病和病媒传播疾病
以及确定有潜在暴发风险地区的基本要素。
决策者和公共卫生官员可以利用由此产生的见解
来准备应对措施、集中监测和分配资源，
以保护人们的生命和生计。
当与气候和环境信息相结合时，
GBIF介导的数据有时可以揭示
甚至预测疾病溢出的地点。
In 2018, an analysis using data from the GBIF network
identified a high-risk hotspot for the Nipah virus outbreak in southern India
just before the disease emerged there.
By contributing to a "One Health" approach
that recognizes the intimate connection
between the well-being of humans, animals, and ecosystems,
data shared through GBIF helps us
understand and prepare for potential disease risks,
reducing the many costs of future disease outbreaks
to keep people and the planet healthy.
To learn more about the connections
GBIF reveals between biodiversity and human health
visit www.gbif.org/health