一個小小的病原體已經提醒我們所有人
人類的健康有多麼地脆弱
且與生態系、其它物種的健康息息相關
世界衛生組織估計
百分之 60 的傳染病源自不同的動物
瞭解能傳播疾病病原的物種
對於辨認、管理及潛在的健康威脅十分重要
有了全球生物多樣性資訊機構（GBIF）上共享的資料
各個不同領域的科學家及研究人員
找出疾病傳染途徑中的相關物種
並查出物種分布的改變情況
這些資料是
瞭解動物及宿主疾病傳播
and identifying areas at risk of potential outbreaks.
Policymakers and public health officials can use the resulting insights
to prepare responses, focus surveillance and allocate resources
to protect people’s lives and livelihoods.
When combined with climatic and environmental information,
GBIF-mediated data sometimes reveals
and even predicts sites of disease spillover.
In 2018, an analysis using data from the GBIF network
identified a high-risk hotspot for the Nipah virus outbreak in southern India
just before the disease emerged there.
By contributing to a "One Health" approach
that recognizes the intimate connection
between the well-being of humans, animals, and ecosystems,
data shared through GBIF helps us
understand and prepare for potential disease risks,
reducing the many costs of future disease outbreaks
to keep people and the planet healthy.
To learn more about the connections
GBIF reveals between biodiversity and human health
visit www.gbif.org/health